<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thorium Reader – Organize</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/</link><description>Recent content in Organize on Thorium Reader</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: The library</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/221_libraries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/221_libraries/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="add-a-book-or-books">Add a book or books&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>you can drag and drop a folder into the library window from your operating system&amp;rsquo;s file browser, and it will be scanned recursively (i.e., the subfolders will also be scanned for publications).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternatively you can select multiple files from your filesystem using your operating system&amp;rsquo;s file browser (the files can be located inside different folders of the tree / hierarchy), then drag and drop the selected publications into Thorium&amp;rsquo;s library window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also click on the &lt;code>+&lt;/code> button in the user interface to open Thorium&amp;rsquo;s file chooser, and from there you can select multiple files from folders, or choose all files in a folder using the operating system&amp;rsquo;s shortcut &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>A&lt;/kbd> or mouse selection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that the &amp;ldquo;open with&amp;rdquo; context menu in the operating system&amp;rsquo;s file explorer will open the reader window(s) for all selected publications, unlike the above methods which only import the files in Thorium&amp;rsquo;s library.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Attention&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorium copies files in a publications subfolder of the EDRLab.ThoriumReader folder. The location of this folder may vary depending on the operating system and may be placed in a hidden folder, you will need to activate display hidden files option to find it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keep in mind that this folder is sensitive because linked to Thorium bookshelf database. For backups or moving from one computer to another, use the &lt;code>Export&lt;/code> button from the book menu. We hope soon to propose an option to export all titles.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="my-books">My Books&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The imported books are presented in the &lt;code>My Books&lt;/code> menu.
It offers a quick access view organized into two sections:
&lt;code>Recently added&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Resume reading&lt;/code>. The &lt;code>All Books&lt;/code>&lt;br>
button will display all the books imported into Thorium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default view is the grid view (&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/icons/baseline-view_module-24px.svg" alt="Icon grid" width="20px"/>), it shows the book covers, title and author.
Clicking on any of these items will open the book in a new
window. A menu for each book allows you to access the &lt;code>Book File&lt;/code>,
&lt;code>Delete&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Export&lt;/code> the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is possible to choose display as a &lt;code>list view&lt;/code> (&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/icons/baseline-view_list-24px.svg" alt="Icon list" width="20px"/>), in this view the cover is no longer
displayed but the year of publication and the publisher are shown.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="all-books">All Books&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>All books&lt;/code> view is organized as a table, it displays all the
information for each book. If information is missing it means that it has not
been provided by the creator of the book. The majority of the
information can be activated and triggers a quick search on the keyword.
For example, click on the word &lt;em>English&lt;/em> in the language column to see only
books in English displayed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The column headers allow you to sort the books in ascending or descending order.
The &lt;code>magnifying glass&lt;/code> icon
(&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/icons/magnifying_glass.svg" alt="" width="20px"/>)
in the header of the first column activates a search field by column
allowing for example to search for an expression only among the titles
of the works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Access to catalogs</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/222_catalogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/222_catalogs/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Many public libraries and bookstores are adopting
&lt;a href="https://opds.io/">OPDS&lt;/a> as a standard format to display their
catalog on the Web. Thorium can provide access to OPDS 1 and 2 catalogs.
It also supports several identification formats associated with OPDS
and can therefore provide users with access to their personal library,
i.e. the digital books that the user has acquired or
borrowed, allowing them to be downloaded and read immediately.
&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>When you are in the Thorium library, select the
&lt;code>Catalogs&lt;/code> tab then the button &lt;code>+ Add an OPDS feed&lt;/code>.
Indicate a Name to designate this catalog and paste an address corresponding to
to a catalog distributed in OPDS format. Validate with the button &lt;code>Add&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example :&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Activating the following link will download a .atom file that can be opened with Thorium:
&lt;a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/search.opds/" target="_blank">Download OPDS feed for Gutenberg.org new titles
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is also possible to use context menu (usually Right clic), Copy this link and paste it into Thorium Add an OPDS panel
to see the magic happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OPDS feeds can also be provided as direct links which should open directly in Thorium. &lt;a href="opds://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/search.opds/" target="_blank">Open OPDS feed for Gutenberg.org new titles&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since Thorium 2.2, OPDS feeds can be edited so you can change the name or retrieve feed URL.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-opds-add.png" alt=""/>
&lt;figcaption class="icon">
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="example-of-opds-feeds-with-lcp-protected-contents">Example of OPDS feeds with LCP protected contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Feeds with protected contents should allow you to login directly from Thorium catalog page, the button or access to login might be different depending on the feed provider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Archive.org OPDS feed allows to browse and borrow books under LCP license. An Archive org account is needed, authentication page will open once you select a book. You can add it to Thorium with the following address: &lt;a href="opds://archive.org/services/opds">Open Archive.org OPDS feed&lt;a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can use &lt;a href="https://catalog.feedbooks.com/catalog/index.json">feedbooks OPDS&lt;/a> to browse &lt;a href="https://www.feedbooks.com/">Feedbook catalog&lt;/a>. Once you have selected a book you&amp;rsquo;ll be redirected to the webpage where you can buy the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feedbooks OPDS allows you to loggin from Thorium Catalog feed with the &lt;em>Shelf&lt;/em> button on the upper right corner. Anybook bought with your Feedbooks account will be available for download directly from the Thorium OPDS feed catalog interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For testing purposes EDRLab provides a feed with three free publications under LCP protection. You can add it to Thorium with the following address: &lt;a href="opds://edrlab.org/public/feed/opds-lcp.json">Add EDRLab OPDS public feed&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="opds-feed-responsibility">OPDS Feed responsibility&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OPDS feeds and the access they provide to content are under responsibility of the feed publisher. So are the information given by the feed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Add tags</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/223_tags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/223_tags/</guid><description>
&lt;p>You can enrich the information of the books in your library by
adding &lt;code>Tags&lt;/code> to them.
`Tags&amp;rsquo; allow you to quickly search and sort books in list view.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Putting it into practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open the book form, position yourself in the field &lt;em>Add a tag&lt;/em>, write
the name of the tag you want to add then press the &lt;code>Add&lt;/code> button.
The tag is added in a blue box, you can remove it by clicking on
the cross.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-tags.png" alt="Screenshot, the search bar is present above the text, the corresponding text is highlighted in green and the Search panel shows 1 match"/></description></item><item><title>Docs: Search</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/223_search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/220_organizing/223_search/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Press the &lt;kbd>Ctrl + F&lt;/kbd> key combination, enter the text you want to search,
press the &lt;code>Results&lt;/code> button, then press the
&lt;kbd>Enter&lt;/kbd> on the link to the desired result.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Activating the Search box will automatically display the &lt;code>All books&lt;/code> view where
it is possible to search in each column.
For example among the authors only.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The search is performed through the books informations including
user added tags.
The content of the book is not included in the search.
To perform a search inside book content you have to open the book and
activate the Search in a book function.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>