<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thorium Reader – Want to collaborate?</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/</link><description>Recent content in Want to collaborate? on Thorium Reader</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Th3: Translating</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/802_localizing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/802_localizing/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Thorium Reader user Interface localisation are provided and maintained thanks to volunteers and contributing organisations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All locales are stored in the sources resources locales folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To add a translation, you can start from the English &amp;ldquo;en.json&amp;rdquo;, rename it as
and change the values after the colon punctuation (:).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are comfortable with github you can open a pull request to submit the file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise you can just send us the localised file by email and we&amp;rsquo;ll proceed to the addition. A list of contributors is maintained on the wiki page Localization (l10n) language translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be aware that we are currently reworking the user interface, so important changes may happen by the first quarter of 2024. We usually alert localisation contributors before any release so they can update the translation file.
Also, mentioning that the thorium documentation website can be localised thru similar contribution methodology. ](../900_about)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Th3: Your help is precious</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/903_support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/903_support/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
You too can help Thorium Reader become the best reading application
reading application by&lt;a href="https://www.edrlab.org/become-a-member/">
becoming a member of EDRLab&lt;/a>.
Or by making a donation to the EDRLab via the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/edrlab">Github sponsorship&lt;/a>
"piggy-bank", which accepts small monthly donations.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Thorium is built by its community. If you want to participate, please
contact us !
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Report an error or suggest a change by opening an Issue
in our
[support tracking tool](https://github.com/edrlab/thorium-reader-doc/issues/new).
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participate in the translation of resources.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Th3: Stuck?</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/904_issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/904_issues/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you do not find the answer to your problem on this site,
you can tell us your problem via our &lt;a href="https://github.com/edrlab/thorium-reader-doc/issues/new">support tracking tool&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.edrlab.org/contact/">contact form&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is the information we need:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Operating system and it version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thorium version (it is indicated at the bottom of the library under the title &lt;code>About Thorium&lt;/code>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Th3: Contribute!</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/905_contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/800_collaborating/905_contribute/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Thorium and its documentation are developed thanks to the user community.
We need help to translate this documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do so, you can
&lt;a href="https://www.edrlab.org/contact/">contact us&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are comfortable enough with GitHub and the Markdown format you can
propose a new translation via a Pull Request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do this: clone the repository and create a branch with the name of the language
you want to add, make a copy of the &lt;code>content.en&lt;/code> folder and rename it with
two letters corresponding to the language you want to add (for example
&lt;code>content.es&lt;/code> will contain the Spanish translation). The names of the files must
not be changed as they insure correspondence between languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>i18n&lt;/code> folder contains the translations for the fixed elements
of the header and footer.
Several languages are already present, if your language is
not present, copy paste the .yaml file and rename it with the first two letters of the
letters of the language you want to add.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally to activate the menu of the language you add, edit the file &lt;code>config.toml&lt;/code>
and add the language with the following code:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>[languages.en]
languageName = &amp;#39;English&amp;#39;
contentDir = &amp;#39;content.en&amp;#39;
weight = 1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>You must replace &lt;code>.en' with the first two letters of the language you are adding and fill in the name of the language as the &lt;/code>languageName&lt;code>value. The&lt;/code>weight` indicates the order of appearance in the language menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example for Spanish :&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>[languages.es]
languageName = &amp;#39;Español&amp;#39;
contentDir = &amp;#39;content.es&amp;#39;
weight = 3
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Localized images such as screenshots should be added to the
folder &lt;code>statics/images/local-(two letter language)&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>