<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thorium Reader – À propos de Thorium Reader</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/</link><description>Recent content in À propos de Thorium Reader on Thorium Reader</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>fr</language><atom:link href="https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Th3: Financement et parrainage</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/901_thorium-sponsorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/901_thorium-sponsorship/</guid><description>
&lt;p>EDRLAB est une organisation à but non lucratif travaillant sur le développement de logiciels open-source, en particulier sur le projet Readium et sur Thorium Reader.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parce que tous les logiciels que nous créons sont gratuits et open-source, et parce que le développement d&amp;rsquo;applications de lecture est vraiment complexe, votre parrainage est nécessaire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Les moyens les plus simples de participer au financement et au parrainage sont:
*&lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/edrlab">Faites un petit don récurrent via le sponsor GitHub&lt;/a>
*&lt;a href="https://members.edrlab.org/join/">Enrôlez votre organisation en tant que membre d&amp;rsquo;Edrlab&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nous sommes également heureux d&amp;rsquo;envisager un financement basé sur le projet, car ainsi, [contactez-nous] (&lt;a href="https://www.edrlab.org/contact/)">https://www.edrlab.org/contact/)&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Th3: Conditions d'utilisation</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/901_thorium-terms-of-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/901_thorium-terms-of-use/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Pour des raisons légales, les conditions d&amp;rsquo;utilisation du logiciel, disponibles en anglais, ne sont pas traduites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vous les trouverez à la page en anglais
&lt;a href="https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/th3/900_about_thorium/901_thorium-terms-of-use/">Terms of use&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Th3: Privacy Policy</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/902_thorium-privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/902_thorium-privacy-policy/</guid><description>
&lt;p>22 November 2022&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="owner-of-the-application">Owner of the application&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>European Digital Reading Lab
14 rue Alexandre Parodi
75010 Paris
France&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="types-of-data-collected">Types of data collected&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The application does not collect Personal Data from its users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The application sends two kinds of non-personal data to servers:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1/ Generic usage data: a notification is sent to an EDRLab telemery server each time the application is started. This information is for analytics only and not accessed by any third party. It is used to get information about the evolution of the number of installs of the application per operating system, the evolution of usage sessions and the main locales in use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parameters of such notification are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a timestamp,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the version of Thorium Reader,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the operating system of the device and its version,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the locale of the application at the time it is started,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if this is the first start of Thorium Reader after a fresh install.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The IP address of the device is not stored along with the above information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is not possible to opt-out from this notification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2/ Readium LCP DRM information: a notification is sent to an LCP Server each time a protected publication is open. This is required by the LCP specification for checking if the license of use of the publication has been updated. There is not centralized LCP Server, each server is operated by the distributor of the protected publication acquired by the user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parameters of such notification are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a device identifier, automatically generated at the install of the application.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a device name, automatically generated at the install of the application.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The codebase of Thorium Reader is open-sourced and can therefore be fully inspected, with the exception of a small software library used as core for the Readium LCP DRM, which does not store or send any data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="updates">Updates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We may change the Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you by posting the revised Privacy Policy on this page and the date on which the last changes were made will be noted at the top of the page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Th3: Credits pour Thorium Reader</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/910_credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/910_credits/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Thorium Reader is currently developed by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul class="nobullet">
&lt;li>Daniel Weck, développeur principal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pierre Leroux, développeur.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arthur Le Meur, développeur&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>L'UX et l'UI de Thorium 3 ont été conçues par &lt;a href="https://www.myleneboyrie.fr/">Mylène Boyrie&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plusieurs autres développeurs ont contribué à faire de Thorium ce qu'il est aujourd'hui :&lt;/p>
&lt;ul class="nobullet">
&lt;li>Simon Le Roux, concepteur d'interface utilisateur.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cyrille Lebeaupin, PDG de noop.fr, développeur senior.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jiminy Panoz, créateur de Readium CSS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leo Stefani, node.js, développeur React.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Manuel Lagrand, stagiaire, développeur node.js.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Le projet est supervisé par Laurent Le Meur, CTO de l'EDRLab.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Qui finance cette application&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
EDRLab est une organisation à but non lucratif. Notre budget provient essentiellement
de la part de nos membres. EDRLab a débuté en France, mais compte désormais 60 membres
d'Europe, d'Amérique du Nord, d'Amérique du Sud et d'Asie.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ce projet n'aurait pas vu le jour sans :&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
1-L'implication financière de nos membres fondateurs : Editis, Hachette
Livre, Magrigall, Médias-Participations, Cercle de la Librarie, Syndicat
nationale de l'Edition. Ils comprennent que le financement des normes ouvertes et
l'open source est le meilleur moyen de dynamiser un marché ouvert et innovant pour
l'industrie de l'édition.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2-Subventions financières des organismes publics français suivants :&lt;/p> &lt;ul>
&lt;li>CNL (Centre National du livre)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ministère de la Culture&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
3-Subventions supplémentaires des membres de l'EDRLab intéressés par l'ajout de
fonctionnalités spécifiques:
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fênix Editorial, Brazil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Canadian Electronic library, Canada&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MLOL / Horizons Unlimited, Italy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lyrasis, USA&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Th3: Licence pour Thorium Reader</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/913_licence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/fr/th3/900_about_thorium/913_licence/</guid><description>
&lt;p>L&amp;rsquo;application Thorium-reader est open-source, publiée sous licence BSD 3. Il est basé sur la boîte à outils open source Readium Desktop sous licence de la &lt;a href="https://readium.org/">Readium Foundation&lt;/a> dans le cadre d&amp;rsquo;un ou plusieurs accords de licence de contributeur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ci après le texte de la licence en anglais :&lt;/p>
&lt;div lang="en">
BSD 3-Clause License
&lt;p>Copyright (c) 2017, EDRLab
All rights reserved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this
list of conditions and the following disclaimer.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice,
this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation
and/or other materials provided with the distribution.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Neither the name of the copyright holder nor the names of its
contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from
this software without specific prior written permission.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &amp;ldquo;AS IS&amp;rdquo;
AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR
SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER
CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE
OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>