<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ressources on Thorium Reader</title>
    <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ressources on Thorium Reader</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/401_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/401_functions/</guid>
      <description>library functions    Icon Function Description Notes Shortcuts      Add book       Next book	       Previous book	       Close (the book information panel)	       Open book menu (gives access to the Book File, allows to Delete and Export a book)	       Search       Book list view       Book grid view	       Indicates that the action is finished, for example when importing a book       Save a copy of the book file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/402_Keyboard-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/402_Keyboard-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Ctrl + F10: Main content(`FocusMain`) in reader and library windows, moves the keyboard focus to the &#34;main&#34; area landmark (in the reader view, this is immediately before the frame that displays publication content)     Ctrl + t: Toolbar (`FocusToolbar`) in reader and library windows, moves the keyboard focus to the top horizontal toolbar, immediately before the &#34;skip&#34; link (which itself moves focus to the &#34;main&#34; area landmark)     Ctrl + n: Navigation (`FocusReaderNavigation`) in reader window, moves the keyboard focus to the navigation panel (table of contents, bookmarks, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supported publication formats</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/406_formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/406_formats/</guid>
      <description>EPUB 2  this is a legacy format, only adequate for basic ebooks. Textual content is formatted in XHTML 1 and no multimedia feature is supported. EPUB 2 ebooks are still accessible if properly formatted.    EPUB 3  this is the recommended format for the 21st century. Textual content is formatted in (X)HTML 5, it is possible to create fixed-layout ebooks, enriched ebooks and accessibiltiy features are well designed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/420_glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/420_glossary/</guid>
      <description>Book information panel (Book Details)  Gives information about the digital book. This information is extracted from the file&#39;s metadata, its quality and quantity depends on the the attention paid during the production of the file by the publisher.    Adapted books These are digital books produced by associations and made available to people with disabilities for reading. Worldwild, this system is governed by The Marrakech Treaty .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently asked questions</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/430_faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/430_faq/</guid>
      <description>I can&#39;t select the adequate voice for read aloud function (TTS) Thorium uses the voices from the computer&#39;s operating system, in combination with the language information provided by the book.  If you are using windows you can follow Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s guide Download the language pack for voice. If you are using Mac OSX the guide Change the voice that the Mac uses to pronounce text.  Once the required voice is installed, Thorium will choose the voice corresponding to the language of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>