<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thorium Reader – Read a book</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/</link><description>Recent content in Read a book on Thorium Reader</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Moving around in a book</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/211_moving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/211_moving/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The navigation options can be very different from one book to another.
Thorium allows the following.
The navigation options can be very different from one book to another. Thorium allows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Move forward and backward in the reading&lt;/li>
&lt;li>use table of contents, reference points and pagination (which must be included by the book&amp;rsquo;s producing organization)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>go to previous and next navigation points&lt;/li>
&lt;li>move backward and forward in the history of navigation actions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="history-navigation-jump-back--forward-to-reading-points-new-in-thorium-22-epub-only">history navigation: jump back &amp;amp; forward to reading points (new in Thorium 2.2. EPUB only)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While reading, user has the power to navigate from one point to another using Navigation panel or following a link into the publication. This activates jump back (&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>backspace&lt;/kbd>) and jump forward (&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>backspace&lt;/kbd>) buttons on the bottom left of the reading window. Use this buttons to find a precedent place and return to the last place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>History Navigation takes into account user interactions, including clicks on bottom timeline, TOC, bookmarks, landmarks, where am I headings, go to page. It does not takes into account search previous and next and list links.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="move-forward-and-backward">Move forward and backward&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To navigate forward and backward in the content of the book you can
use the arrows on your keyboard or click on the navigation arrows
located at the bottom right of the reading interface
(&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/icons/baseline-arrow_left_ios-24px.svg" alt="Previous content button" width="15px"/>&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/icons/baseline-arrow_forward_ios-24px.svg" alt="Next content button" width="15px"/>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is possible to move between chapters using
&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Previous page (Page Up)&lt;/kbd> (previous chapter) and
&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Next page (Page Down)&lt;/kbd> (next chapter)
or &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>ALT&lt;/kbd>
(except on MacOS) + &lt;kbd>←&lt;/kbd>
(previous chapter)
and &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>ALT&lt;/kbd>
(except on MacOS) + &lt;kbd>→&lt;/kbd>
(next chapter).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Attention!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two different shortcuts to go to the next or previous chapter.
Depending on your configuration and whether or not you use a screen reader,
it is possible that only one of these two combinations works.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="the-table-of-contents">The table of contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The table of contents represents the architecture of the book as defined by
the book&amp;rsquo;s producing organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first level titles are indicated without margin, those with
subtitles (or second level title) are presented with a lightgray background.
The sub-headings are shifted from the margin to the left and a
vertical line makes it easy to know
to which level of title they belong.&lt;/p>
&lt;details >&lt;summary>With NVDA&lt;/summary>
&lt;div class="markdown-inner">
You can use the title level navigation functions
(&lt;kbd>NVDA&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>H&lt;/kbd>)
to explore and move through the table of contents.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/details>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-TDM-light.png" alt="Screenshot, table of contents: Titles Level 1 Cover, Title, Copyright, Dedicae, Exergue, Introduction, The Mark of Four; Title Level 2 Deduction elevated to a science."/>
&lt;h2 id="landmarks">Landmarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Good-quality digital books have markers that allow you to
identify and quickly reach the main parts of a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each EPUB publication should include a guide to all major
landmarks. The titles of the landmarks are at the discretion of the publisher
choice, but the nature of each landmark must be identified according to a
semantic vocabulary. The main ones are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Main text (bodymatter)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Table of contents (toc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bibliography&lt;/li>
&lt;li>index&lt;/li>
&lt;li>glossary&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/epub-ssv/">complete list of semantic vocabulary EPUB in English&lt;/a>
is available on the W3C website.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-reperes.png" alt="Screenshot, Go to page. Current page: 3. A drop-down menu indicates 3, an editable field indicates Enter page number, a button indicates Go to."/>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Attention !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PDF bookmarks used to compensate for the lack of a table of contents
in this format are not interpreted by Thorium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike Landmarks, Bookmarks are made for users who want to place a mark into a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="the-reference-pages">The reference pages&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Digital books can have a reference pagination allowing
correspondence to the pagination of the printed book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a navigation option to go to the page.
When you access it, this option shows the current page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is also a keyboard shortcut for this function. Press the
&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>P&lt;/kbd>,
then enter the page number in the edit box by typing it or
changing the value using the &lt;code>Go to page&lt;/code> box.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-gotopage.png" alt="Screenshot, Go to page. Current page: 3. A drop-down menu indicates 3, an editable field indicates Enter page number, a button indicates Go to."/>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Attention !&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://thorium.edrlab.org/thorium-reader-doc/400_ressources/420_glossary#AdaptedBooks">
Adapted books&lt;/a> sometimes use the reference pagination to offer a regular
book breakdown to readers without reproducing the pagination of the
original pagination. In this case the reference pagination cannot be used
to refer to the printed book.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Where am I?</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/212_whereami/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/212_whereami/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The keyboard shortcuts &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>k&lt;/kbd>
allows to get a quick mention of the reading position in the document.
This information will be displayed in the notification area at the bottom left
of the interface and will be read by a screen reader.&lt;/p>
&lt;details >&lt;summary>Screen reader&amp;rsquo;s page location is approximative&lt;/summary>
&lt;div class="markdown-inner">
&lt;p>Because of inherent limitation in current screen reader technology, Thorium has to estimates the reading location. Consequently the page number anounced by Thorium is not reflecting the place where the screen reader&amp;rsquo;s is actually reading, the error might be of some sentences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This &lt;a href="https://github.com/edrlab/thorium-reader/issues/1662#issuecomment-1161534338">screenreader page location issue&lt;/a> is known and we are discuting about a way to solve &lt;a href="https://github.com/edrlab/thorium-reader/discussions/1799">accessible page numbers &amp;amp; page breaks&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However NVDA will announce the page break as a separator if it has a title attribute (exemple: &lt;code> &amp;lt;span epub:type=&amp;quot;pagebreak&amp;quot; role=&amp;quot;doc-pagebreak&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;page_2&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;page&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/code> will cause NVDA to anounce &amp;ldquo;Two, separator&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/details>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-whereami-ctrlK.png" alt="Screenshot, notification area, current page 103 - progress = 14/25 (barrel incident) [32%] H1 VII / H2 Barrel incident."/>
&lt;p>The keyboard shortcut &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>n&lt;/kbd> will open the table of content Navigation menu centered and focused to the detected heading closest to the reading location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you look at the &lt;code>Navigation&lt;/code> menu, Thorium shows the current chapter
in the &lt;code>table of contents&lt;/code> and the current page in the &lt;code>Go to page&lt;/code> menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-whereami-tdmfocus.png" alt="Screenshot, reading a book with title VII Barrel Incident. The navigation pane is open, the table of contents shows the title Barrel Incident in a square which indicates that this is the chapter being read."/>
&lt;h1 id="access-more-informations">Access more informations&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Use the &lt;em>Information&lt;/em> function (&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>I&lt;/kbd>)
to open a panel that displays the title structure and page number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the book information, this sign shows at the subheading Progression:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the chapter number out of the total number of chapters;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the title of the current chapter;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the percentage read of the current chapter;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the current page;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the title structure (h1 is a level 1 title, h2 is a level 2 title, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Press the &lt;kbd>Escape&lt;/kbd> key to close the &lt;code>Information&lt;/code> panel
and return to the text.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-progression.png" alt="Screenshot, progress: 14/25 (barrel incident) [1%] h1: VII"/>
&lt;details >&lt;summary>Use &lt;strong>Where am I&lt;/strong> with NVDA&lt;/summary>
&lt;div class="markdown-inner">
&lt;p>Press the &lt;kbd>NVDA&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>F7&lt;/kbd> keys, and then the
tab key until you get the header view.
This shows you where you are in the title structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Press the &lt;kbd>NVDA&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Enter&lt;/kbd> keys to save the current position.
Then &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>I&lt;/kbd> to place the
cursor in the Progress section of the dialog box containing information about the
information dialog box. The number of the current HTML document in relation to the
the total number of documents, the percentage, the current page and the corresponding
section are displayed, with the option of displaying links to
scroll backwards and forwards. After closing the dialog, for example by
for example by pressing &lt;kbd>Escape&lt;/kbd> key, it is possible to return to the point
through the screen reader link (marked with a double underline) in the main
underline) in the main content frame (which can be navigated to with the
with the &lt;kbd>Tab&lt;/kbd> key or with the letter &lt;kbd>M&lt;/kbd> in navigation mode).&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/details></description></item><item><title>Docs: Zooming on images</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/212_imagezoom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/212_imagezoom/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Since 2.3, Thorium has an image zoom feature (epub only).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To zoom on an image you can select the image (a magenta focus outline will appear around it) and activate zoom by clicking with the mouse or tapping it with the finger. Access to image zoom via keyboard is currently not possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the image is also a link or if the book your read is in a fixed layout format, you will need to hit the &lt;kbd>Shift&lt;/kbd> key in order to enter the image zoom feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To zoom in or out, tab to the &lt;code>+&lt;/code> or &lt;code>-&lt;/code> buttons and hit &lt;kbd>enter&lt;/kbd>, use mouse wheel, scroll up and down or pinch and stretch trackpad or onscreen touch gestures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the image is zoomed you can move vertically and horizontally with &lt;kbd>←&lt;/kbd>, &lt;kbd>→&lt;/kbd>, &lt;kbd>↑&lt;/kbd> and &lt;kbd>↓&lt;/kbd>, by holding down the mouse button and moving the mouse, with usual trackpad gestures or with finger moves on tactile screens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To close the image zoom view and to return to the reading view, press &lt;kbd>ESC&lt;/kbd> key, or the X button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some restrictions due to ebook design may apply, for example when images are inserted as style (CSS), it is not possible to open the image view for zooming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Search in a book</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/213_search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/213_search/</guid><description>
&lt;p>You can use &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>F&lt;/kbd> keys to access the
search field. Enter your search term. By clicking on the
&lt;code>Search&lt;/code> button, you get &lt;code>Back&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Next&lt;/code> buttons to navigate between occurences.
The number of matches found is a link that will open a &lt;code>List of results&lt;/code>
in the right panel.
Each match displayed is a link you can Activate to go to the place
of the book where the expression you are looking for was found.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Remember that performing a search and navigating through the results
will make you loose the reading point you where at.
Just place a Bookmark to make sure you find your way back.
&lt;/div>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-search-navpanel.png" alt="Screenshot, the search bar is present above the text, the corresponding text highlighted in green and the Search panel indicates a match"/></description></item><item><title>Docs: Mark a page or a passage</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/214_bookmarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/214_bookmarks/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="add-a-bookmark">Add a bookmark&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>bookmark&lt;/code> button allows you to add a custom bookmark.
A &lt;code>bookmark&lt;/code> can be a fixed point or a text selection.
Only one fixed point bookmark is possible per page
(book pages or calculated pages in case there is not page reference in the book).
But you can place as many texte selection bookmark as you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you add a &lt;code>Bookmark&lt;/code> a notification appears to inform you that
the &lt;code>Bookmark&lt;/code> was &lt;em>Added&lt;/em> or &lt;em>Deleted&lt;/em>.
The number just after indicates the total number of &lt;code>Bookmarks&lt;/code> in the Book
after this action.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Select the text you want to mark.
Press the &lt;code>bookmark&lt;/code> button
(&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/icons/outline-bookmark-24px-grey.svg" alt="" width="20px"/>)
or the key combination &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>B&lt;/kbd>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If no text is selected so the full page will be marked.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="reviewing-and-navigating-the-bookmarks">Reviewing and navigating the Bookmarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Press the &lt;code>Navigation&lt;/code> button (&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>N&lt;/kbd>), then
the &lt;code>Bookmarks&lt;/code> button. You can change the name of each bookmark, delete
bookmarks and move between bookmarks by pressing &lt;kbd>Enter&lt;/kbd>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Access the list of bookmarks in the navigation area. Select the bookmark
you wish to access and press the &lt;kbd>Enter&lt;/kbd> key. If you have
renamed the bookmark, it will be easy to go to several places in the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Advice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you select a portion of text and then activate the &lt;code>Bookmark&lt;/code> button,
the bookmark created will have the selected line as its title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have bookmarked a line without selecting a portion of text, try copying
the line you are on in the clipboard.
Then go to the navigation options with &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>N&lt;/kbd>,
then scroll down to the Bookmark section, where they are listed.
Press the &lt;kbd>b&lt;/kbd> key to move to the edit button to
rename the bookmark. Paste the line from the clipboard and press
&lt;kbd>Enter&lt;/kbd>. This renames the bookmark with the line of text that you have
copied. When you have several bookmarks, this renaming of the bookmarks allows
you to use them easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-marquePages.png" alt=""/>
&lt;figcaption class="icon">
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;details >&lt;summary>Using bookmarks with NVDA&lt;/summary>
&lt;div class="markdown-inner">
Windows screen readers use a virtual buffer
for reading. To place a bookmark where you are currently reading
press the key combination &lt;kbd>NVDA + Enter&lt;/kbd>,
and NVDA will say &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;activate &amp;ldquo;&lt;/em>. This
synchronizes the virtual buffer with the current real location so Thorium
can deduce the object
on which the cursor is located. Then use
&lt;kbd>Ctrl + B&lt;/kbd> to place a bookmark.
A sound notification will inform you of the number of bookmarks
in the current publication.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/details></description></item><item><title>Docs: Reading settings</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/215_readingparameters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/215_readingparameters/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In the reading interface use the &lt;code>Preferences&lt;/code> button (&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/icons/font-size.svg" alt="" width="20px"/>): the options are revealed.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Reading settings can be saved or reset by using buttons &lt;code>Save&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Reset&lt;/code> located in the menu &lt;code>Settings&lt;/code>, submenu &lt;code>Configuration&lt;/code> of the Reading window.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Major settings are available for EPUB Reflowable, Fixed Layout EPUBs and PDF formats just don&amp;rsquo;t allow personalisation of appearance. Most Fixed Layout EPUBs will allow to open Image view for zooming on a page. PDFs can be enlarged using the Zoom sub-menu in the Preferences panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="theme">Theme&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The color of the background and foreground can be changed using one of the three
available themes - Neutral, Sepia and Night.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="text">Text&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The font size can be increased or decreased using the slider.
The font can also be changed. The available options are as follows
Default, Old style, Modern, Sans, Humanist, Readable (Dyslexia),
Dualspace and Monospace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By selecting the &lt;code>...&lt;/code> you can enter the name of the font you want to use.
To do this, the font must be present on your
operating system and you must know its exact name as it is set for
the operating system.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h3 id="example-1-setting-verdana-as-the-reading-font">Example 1: Setting Verdana as the reading font&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In the reading interface go to the &lt;code>Preference&lt;/code> menu and then &lt;code>Text&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the drop-down list select &lt;code>...&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Write the word &lt;em>Verdana&lt;/em> in the empty field that appears next to the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirm with &lt;kbd>Enter&lt;/kbd>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-verdana.png" alt="Screenshot showing the Text settings Pannel with verdana set up as reading font"/>
&lt;h3 id="example-2-setting-up-luciole-as-the-reading-font">Example 2: Setting up Luciole as the reading font&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.luciole-vision.com/Fichiers/Luciole-Regular.ttf">Download and install the Luciole font&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the reading interface go to the &lt;code>Preference&lt;/code> menu and then &lt;code>Text&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the drop-down list select &lt;code>...&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Write the word &lt;em>Luciole&lt;/em> in the empty field that appears next to the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirm with &lt;kbd>Enter&lt;/kbd>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;img class="icons" src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-luciole.png" alt="Screenshot showing the Text settings Pannel with Luciole set up as reading font"/>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="display">Display&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can choose between a page layout with scrolling or pagination,
automatic or justified alignment and automatic or
on 1 or 2 columns. Here also, MathJax can be activated, for the display of
mathematical expressions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="spacing">Spacing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Margins, word spacing, letter spacing, paragraph spacing and line spacing
can be adjusted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="readaloud">Readaloud&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Provides options for an uncluttered &lt;code>clean view&lt;/code> and the ability to skip
secondary content (&lt;code>skippability&lt;/code>) which may include
footnotes or sidebars according to the semantics
indicated during the production of the digital book.
&lt;code>Split TTS&lt;/code> will split the content by sentence for more precise highlighting.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Thorium uses the voices from the computer&amp;rsquo;s operating system, in combination with the language information provided by the book. If you experience problems please check the related FAQ entry &lt;a href="../400_ressources/430_faq#TTSvoices">I can&amp;rsquo;t select the adequate voice for read aloud function (TTS)&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Read mathematics</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/221_maths/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/221_maths/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Since 2.3 Thorium Reader supports mathematical formulas in MathML natively thanks to Chromium.
MathJax module is incorporated and may be of use for interoperability and accessibility needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you make use of the MathJax module you might be interested by &lt;a href="https://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/">MathJax documentation&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous versions rely on the MathJax module. This last one requires memory resources
so it is not automatically activated when you open Thorium.
To activate it when reading a book, go to the
menu &lt;code>Reading settings&lt;/code>, at the bottom of the &lt;code>Display&lt;/code> tab you will find
a checkbox &lt;code>MathJax&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-mathjax.png" alt="Screenshot of a complex mathematical formula correctly displayed with the MathJax option checked."/>
&lt;p>Once MathJax is activated, you can use the &lt;code>contextual menu&lt;/code> (right click)
on a mathematical formula inserted in MathML format and use the many
options proposed such as reading aloud (speech), viewing the semantic marking
or copy the formula with its semantic attributes to use it in a
compatible editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://thorium.edrlab.org/images/local-fr/thorium-mathjax-menu.png" alt="Screenshot of the MathJax context menu showing the Accessibility sub-menu with the Activate option checked."/>
&lt;details >&lt;summary>Read &lt;strong>mathematics&lt;/strong> with NVDA&lt;/summary>
&lt;div class="markdown-inner">
&lt;p>You can read mathematical expressions tagged with MathML using
different NVDA approaches. Although NVDA is already equipped with this feature by applying Math Player, some functions still needed to be improved, especially in Math Player some language support is not provided. You may want to use an addon like &lt;a href="https://addons.nvda-project.org/addons/MathCAT.en.html">MathCAT&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://addons.nvda-project.org/addons/access8math.fr.html">Access8Math&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In case of instabilities, we recommend to disable MathJax accessibility features through context menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using Access8Math:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To install the add-on, navigate to Access8Math webpage and click on “Stable” link to download the add-on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When reading a EPUB with Math content, Down Arrow to the line containing the equation and place your focus on the equation.
Press Enter to activate &amp;ldquo;Access8Math.
This will open a small window containing interaction window&amp;rdquo; which contains &amp;ldquo;interactive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;copy&amp;rdquo; buttons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interaction: This will allow Interaction within the math content. In order to navigate and browse, you can use the Down Arrow to partially explore the subparts in the expression and move or zoom the content between the subparts by using Right and Left Arrows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copy: Use the Copy mode to Copy MathML object source code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navigation mode commands:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Down Arrow&lt;/kbd>: Zoom in on a smaller subpart of the math content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Up Arrow&lt;/kbd>: Zoom out to a larger sub-part of the math content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Left Arrow&lt;/kbd>: Move to the previous math content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Right Arrow&lt;/kbd>: Move to the next math content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Home&lt;/kbd>: Move back to the top of the Entire math content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>c&lt;/kbd>: Copy object MathML source code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Numpad 1 to 9&lt;/kbd>: Reading the math content into serialized text using NVDA Review Text.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Escape&lt;/kbd>: Exit the navigation mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>Alt&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>m&lt;/kbd>: Switch the provider between Access8Math and Math Player.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/details>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;p>Attention !
These features can only be activated if the book has been designed by
inserting mathematical formulas in the MathML format. For reasons of
ease of production the mathematical formulas are often included as&lt;br>
images and it is then the alternative text that must allow the
understanding of the formula via a precise description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Books that include mathematics in MathML form should
indicate this in their accessibility information.
If this is not indicated, then they are certainly described images.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Text to Speech (TTS)</title><link>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/230_tts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thorium.edrlab.org/en/docs/210_reading/230_tts/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Text-to-speech functionalities are available only with EPUB and Daisy formats.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Text-to-speech is launched using the speaker button in the middle of the toolbar,
or by using the keyboard shortcut &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>2&lt;/kbd>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Play and pause can be controlled with the keyboard shortcut
&lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>2&lt;/kbd>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The playback position can be moved with &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>1&lt;/kbd>
and &lt;kbd>Ctrl&lt;/kbd> + &lt;kbd>3&lt;/kbd> for previous and next respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A speed control is available when read aloud
is selected, with a range from x0.5 to x2.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The current sentence is highlighted in light yellow, and each word spoken is
underlined in orange.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="options-for-tts">Options for TTS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Three options are available in the &lt;code>Settings / Readaloud&lt;/code> menu:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Simplified view auto scrolls text with focus by paragraphe.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Skippability does not display auxiliary contents authored as footnotes, endnotes, pagebreaks and asides.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Split text focuses phrase by phrase&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Thorium uses the voices from the computer&amp;rsquo;s operating system, in combination with the language information provided by the book. If you experience problems please check the related FAQ entry &lt;a href="https://thorium.edrlab.org/docs/400_ressources/430_faq#TTSvoices">I can&amp;rsquo;t select the adequate voice for read aloud function (TTS)&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Thorium 2.3 TTS reads page numbers by default which might result in a too verbose earing experience. The &lt;code>skipability&lt;/code> option in &lt;code>readaloud&lt;/code> parameter does not affect TTS reading as expected. This is fixed in &lt;a href="https://github.com/edrlab/thorium-reader/releases">2.4 alpha continuous test build&lt;/a> and will be shipped in 2.4 release.
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>