<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Read a book on Thorium Reader</title>
    <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Read a book on Thorium Reader</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving around in a book</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/211_moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/211_moving/</guid>
      <description>The navigation options can be very different from one book to another. Thorium allows the following. The navigation options can be very different from one book to another. Thorium allows:
 Move forward and backward in the reading use table of contents, reference points and pagination (which must be included by the book&amp;rsquo;s producing organization) go to previous and next navigation points move backward and forward in the history of navigation actions  history navigation: jump back &amp;amp; forward to reading points (new in Thorium 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where am I?</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/212_whereAmI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/212_whereAmI/</guid>
      <description>The keyboard shortcuts Shift + Ctrl + k allows to get a quick mention of the reading position in the document. This information will be displayed in the notification area at the bottom left of the interface and will be read by a screen reader.
Screen reader&amp;rsquo;s page location is approximative Because of inherent limitation in current screen reader technology, Thorium has to estimates the reading location. Consequently the page number anounced by Thorium is not reflecting the place where the screen reader&amp;rsquo;s is actually reading, the error might be of some sentences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search in a book</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/213_search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/213_search/</guid>
      <description>You can use Ctrl + F keys to access the search field. Enter your search term. By clicking on the Search button, you get Back and Next buttons to navigate between occurences. The number of matches found is a link that will open a List of results in the right panel. Each match displayed is a link you can Activate to go to the place of the book where the expression you are looking for was found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark a page or a passage</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/214_bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/214_bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Add a bookmark The bookmark button allows you to add a custom bookmark. A bookmark can be a fixed point or a text selection. Only one fixed point bookmark is possible per page (book pages or calculated pages in case there is not page reference in the book). But you can place as many texte selection bookmark as you want.
When you add a Bookmark a notification appears to inform you that the Bookmark was Added or Deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading settings</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/215_ReadingParameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/215_ReadingParameters/</guid>
      <description>In the reading interface use the Preferences button (): the following options are revealed.
Theme The color of the background and foreground can be changed using one of the three available themes - Neutral, Sepia and Night.
Text The font size can be increased or decreased using the slider. The font can also be changed. The available options are as follows Default, Old style, Modern, Sans, Humanist, Readable (Dyslexia), Dualspace and Monospace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read mathematics</title>
      <link>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/221_maths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edrlab.github.io/thorium-reader-doc/210_reading/221_maths/</guid>
      <description>Thorium-Reader supports mathematical formulas in MathML format thanks to the MathJax module. This last one requires memory resources so it is not automatically activated when you open Thorium. To activate it when reading a book, go to the menu Reading settings, at the bottom of the Display tab you will find a checkbox MathJax.
Once MathJax is activated, you can use the contextual menu (right click) on a mathematical formula inserted in MathML format and use the many options proposed such as reading aloud (speech), viewing the semantic marking or copy the formula with its semantic attributes to use it in a compatible editor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>